<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Security on Peak Defence - Your Cybersecurity Wingman</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/tags/security/</link><description>Recent content in Security on Peak Defence - Your Cybersecurity Wingman</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 18:37:15 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://peakdefence.com/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction to the Peak Defence Method</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/resources/method/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peakdefence.com/resources/method/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="why-this-methodology-exists">Why This Methodology Exists&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Security in today&amp;rsquo;s organizations faces a fundamental challenge: the approaches that worked in the past are failing to deliver sustainable value in increasingly complex, fast-moving environments.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This statement is likely to stay true for as long as environments we operate in keep changing, and that might always be the case, at least for most of the organizations. Despite growing security investments, many struggle with:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Security teams isolated from the business, creating friction rather than enablement&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Security controls that focus on prevention but fail to adapt when breaches occur&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Security work that expands indefinitely without clear boundaries or completion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Siloed approaches that prevent effective cross-functional collaboration&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rigid methodologies that don&amp;rsquo;t scale with organizational growth&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The Peak Defence Method addresses these challenges through a fundamentally different approach to security — one that prioritizes resilience over rigid prevention, balances centralized expertise with distributed responsibility, and delivers visible value through bounded, focused work.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>