<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Introduction to the Peak Defence Method on Peak Defence - Your Cybersecurity Wingman</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/resources/method/</link><description>Recent content in Introduction to the Peak Defence Method on Peak Defence - Your Cybersecurity Wingman</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 12:50:13 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://peakdefence.com/resources/method/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Core Principles and Philosophy</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/resources/method/core/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peakdefence.com/resources/method/core/</guid><description>&lt;!-- # Core Principles of Peak Defence Method -->
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Security approaches often fail not because of poor implementation, but because they&amp;rsquo;re built on flawed assumptions about the nature of security itself. The Peak Defence Method is founded on a different perspective — one that acknowledges the inherent complexity and unpredictability of modern systems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This chapter explains the philosophical foundation and core principles that guide our approach across organizations of all sizes and maturity levels. These principles inform every aspect of the methodology, from how we &lt;a href="shaping.md">shape work&lt;/a> to how we implement security controls and measure security effectiveness.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Planning Horizons</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/resources/method/planning/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peakdefence.com/resources/method/planning/</guid><description>&lt;!-- # Planning Horizons -->
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Effective security requires working across multiple time horizons simultaneously. Without a structured approach to planning, organizations typically face these common challenges:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Strategic initiatives get interrupted by tactical and urgent needs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Long-term architectural decisions lack follow-through&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Short-term work doesn&amp;rsquo;t align with strategic direction&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Teams lose context when switching between immediate and long-term work&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Security priorities constantly shift, creating waste and confusion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cross-functional dependencies create bottlenecks and misalignment&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Security requirements are introduced too late in product or business processes&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The Four Horizons Framework provides a structured way to organize security initiatives across different timescales, ensuring that both strategic long-term objectives and tactical immediate needs receive appropriate attention. It also creates natural connection points with other organizational functions, enabling more effective cross-functional security work. This chapter explains how organizations of all sizes can implement this framework at their appropriate maturity level.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shaping Security Work</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/resources/method/shaping/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peakdefence.com/resources/method/shaping/</guid><description>&lt;!-- # Shaping Security Work -->
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Security initiatives fail for many reasons, but often there is a common pattern: &lt;strong>they&amp;rsquo;re either too vague or too specific before implementation begins&lt;/strong>. Traditional approaches oscillate between these extremes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Too abstract&lt;/strong>: &amp;ldquo;Implement zero trust architecture&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Improve our security posture&amp;rdquo; lack clear boundaries and direction&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Too concrete&lt;/strong>: Detailed specifications that over-constrain implementation teams and can&amp;rsquo;t adapt to discoveries made during implementation&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Shaping security work is the critical process that bridges this gap. It creates &lt;strong>just enough structure&lt;/strong> to enable teams to deliver meaningful security improvements within fixed time constraints, while leaving room for adaptation and expertise.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Security Roles and Responsibilities</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/resources/method/roles/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peakdefence.com/resources/method/roles/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Effective security outcomes depend not just on what we do, but on &lt;strong>who does it&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>how responsibilities are distributed&lt;/strong>. Many security initiatives fail despite solid technical foundations because:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Security responsibilities are unclear or undefined&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The wrong people make security decisions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Crucial stakeholders aren&amp;rsquo;t involved at the right time&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cross-functional dependencies aren&amp;rsquo;t managed effectively&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Security requirements aren&amp;rsquo;t translated for different audiences&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Security responsibilities don&amp;rsquo;t scale with organizational growth&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The Peak Defence Method defines a flexible framework for security roles and responsibilities that:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>