<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Your Cybersecurity AI Wingman: Where Human Expertise Meets Intelligent Automation on PEAK DEFENCE - Your Cybersecurity Wingman</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/</link><description>Recent content in Your Cybersecurity AI Wingman: Where Human Expertise Meets Intelligent Automation on PEAK DEFENCE - Your Cybersecurity Wingman</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://peakdefence.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What AI Means for Your Security Team</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/blog/what-ai-means-for-your-security-team/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 04:14:54 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://peakdefence.com/blog/what-ai-means-for-your-security-team/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="what-ai-means-for-your-security-team---breaking-the-manual-cycle">What AI Means for Your Security Team - Breaking the Manual Cycle&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="the-real-world-impact-of-ai-on-security-management---from-someone-whos-been-in-the-trenches">The Real-World Impact of AI on Security Management - From Someone Who&amp;rsquo;s Been in the Trenches&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been through more security audits than I can count. Both, conducting them and being on the receiving end. I&amp;rsquo;ve sat on the auditor&amp;rsquo;s side of the table, watching teams scramble to provide evidence for controls they claim to have. I&amp;rsquo;ve been on the auditee side too, working late nights to gather documentation, chasing system owners, and frantically updating tracking spreadsheets.I&amp;rsquo;ve been involved in a ton of security audits, both as the one doing the auditing and the one being audited. When I&amp;rsquo;m the auditor, I often see teams scramble to prove they actually have the security controls they say they do. And when I&amp;rsquo;m the one being audited, I&amp;rsquo;ve pulled plenty of all-nighters gathering documentation, chasing down system owners, and frantically trying to keep those tracking spreadsheets up to date.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Backend / Full-Stack Developer</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/careers/backend-developer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://peakdefence.com/careers/backend-developer/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="mission-connection">Mission Connection&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As a Backend/Full-Stack Developer, you&amp;rsquo;ll be at the core of our mission to transform how organizations manage security through the perfect balance of People, Process, and Technology. You&amp;rsquo;ll build the systems that power our Wingman platform, with a focus on implementing AI capabilities and creating intuitive user interfaces.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="role-overview">Role Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ll design and build the systems that power our Wingman platform, with a focus on implementing AI capabilities and creating intuitive user interfaces. You&amp;rsquo;ll work closely with our security experts to translate complex security concepts into elegant technical solutions that help our customers achieve better security outcomes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Client Success Security Consultant</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/careers/security-consultant/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://peakdefence.com/careers/security-consultant/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="mission-connection">Mission Connection&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As a Client Success Security Consultant, you&amp;rsquo;ll be at the forefront of Peak Defence&amp;rsquo;s mission to transform security management through the perfect integration of People, Process, and Technology. You&amp;rsquo;ll work directly with clients to implement our methodology, ensuring they achieve meaningful security outcomes rather than just checking compliance boxes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="role-overview">Role Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Unlike traditional consultants who primarily give advice, you&amp;rsquo;ll be hands-on in implementing solutions, driving adoption of our methodology, and ensuring clients achieve measurable security improvements. You&amp;rsquo;ll work across the entire security lifecycle: from initial assessment through implementation, optimization, and ongoing management.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Privacy Policy</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/privacy-policy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://peakdefence.com/privacy-policy/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="1-introduction">1. Introduction&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>This Privacy Policy applies to the Virtual CISO services provided by Peak Defence (&amp;ldquo;Services&amp;rdquo;). It explains how we handle data in the course of providing these Services.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="2-data-processing-and-personal-data">2. Data Processing and Personal Data&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The Services are designed not to process personal data. There is no expectation or requirement for users to upload personal data into the product and this would contradict the Terms of service.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="3-data-hosting-and-processing">3. Data Hosting and Processing&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The Services are hosted on AWS infrastructure located within the European Union (EU) - or in other regions if specifically contracted with customers. AWS acts as a data processor on behalf of Peak Defence.
Langfuse is another data processor used for the hosted service (for deployments under Starter package, starting from Scaleup and Enterprise packages a different deployment model can be negotiated), under strict data protection agreements - they receive the queries data made against the service and responses to the queries, but not the original data / documents used to create answers.
Users have the option to run a local version of the Services on AWS, or for Enterprise versions, a hosted version where no data leaves the customer&amp;rsquo;s premises.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About Peak Defence</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/company/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peakdefence.com/company/</guid><description>&lt;!-- # About Peak Defence -->
&lt;h2 id="our-mission">Our Mission&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Peak Defence exists to transform how organizations manage security through the perfect integration of People, Process, and Technology. We believe security should be intelligent, accessible, and effective for every organization.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="our-story">Our Story&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Founded by a team of security leaders willing to challenge the status quo and outdated approaches, Peak Defence was born from a simple observation: security management was broken. Organizations were drowning in manual processes, struggling with disconnected tools, and failing to achieve meaningful security outcomes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Contact Us</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peakdefence.com/contact/</guid><description>&lt;p>Whether you&amp;rsquo;re interested in learning more about our platform, scheduling a demo, or discussing how we can help with your security challenges, our team is here to assist. Fill out the form below, and one of our specialists will get back to you shortly.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Peak Defence Methodology</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/methodology/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peakdefence.com/methodology/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction-a-balanced-approach-to-security">Introduction: A Balanced Approach to Security&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Peak Defence Methodology represents a fundamental shift in how organizations approach information security. Rather than treating security as a series of technical controls or compliance checkboxes, our methodology centers on the perfect integration of &lt;strong>People&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Process&lt;/strong>, and &lt;strong>Technology&lt;/strong> to create resilient, proactive security programs that deliver measurable outcomes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our approach is born from years of experience witnessing the same patterns across organizations of all sizes: manual processes creating bottlenecks, reactive approaches leaving vulnerabilities unaddressed, and disconnected systems preventing comprehensive visibility. The Peak Defence Methodology, powered by our Wingman AI platform, breaks this cycle.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Schedule a Demo</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/demo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peakdefence.com/demo/</guid><description>&lt;div class="meetings-iframe-container" data-src="https://meetings-eu1.hubspot.com/roman-jasins?embed=true">&lt;/div>
&lt;script type="text/javascript" src="https://static.hsappstatic.net/MeetingsEmbed/ex/MeetingsEmbedCode.js">&lt;/script>

&lt;style>
 .meetings-iframe-container {
 min-width: 320px;
 height: 700px;
 transition: height .2s ease;
 margin-top: 2rem;
 }
 
 @media (max-width: 640px) {
 .meetings-iframe-container {
 height: 800px;
 }
 }
&lt;/style></description></item><item><title>Security Services</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/solutions/security-services/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peakdefence.com/solutions/security-services/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="security-services-that-balance-expertise-and-efficiency">Security Services That Balance Expertise and Efficiency&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Peak Defence&amp;rsquo;s Security Services combine seasoned security professionals with innovative methodologies to deliver security guidance that makes a real difference. Unlike traditional consulting, our approach focuses on implementation and measurable outcomes, not just recommendations.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="our-core-services">Our Core Services&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="virtual-ciso-services">Virtual CISO Services&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Gain access to executive-level security leadership without the cost of a full-time CISO.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Key Components:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Strategic security program development and roadmapping&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Security governance and policy framework implementation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Board and executive stakeholder communication&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Security budget planning and resource allocation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cross-functional security coordination&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>How It Works:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Strategic Partnerships</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/partnerships/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peakdefence.com/partnerships/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="collaborate-with-us">Collaborate With Us&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We believe that meaningful partnerships can create exceptional value for our customers and partners alike. While we&amp;rsquo;re selective about our collaborations, we&amp;rsquo;re always interested in connecting with organizations that share our vision for transforming security management through the perfect integration of People, Process, and Technology.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="our-partnership-philosophy">Our Partnership Philosophy&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Rather than maintaining a standard partnership program, we take a highly curated approach to building strategic relationships. This allows us to:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Terms of Service</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/terms-of-service/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peakdefence.com/terms-of-service/</guid><description>&lt;p>These Terms of Service govern your use of the Peak Defence platform and services. By using our services, you agree to these terms which include important information about:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Your responsibilities when using our platform&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Subscription terms and payment obligations&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Data ownership and confidentiality&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Limitations of liability&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Intellectual property rights&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Please read these terms carefully before using our services.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thank You for Your Application</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/thank-you/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peakdefence.com/thank-you/</guid><description>&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="layout-thank-you">title: &amp;ldquo;Thank You for Contacting Us&amp;rdquo;
description: &amp;ldquo;Your message has been received and we&amp;rsquo;ll be in touch soon&amp;rdquo;
layout: &amp;ldquo;thank-you&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="message-received">Message Received&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Thank you for reaching out to Peak Defence! We&amp;rsquo;ve received your message and our team will review it promptly.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-happens-next">What happens next?&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Initial review&lt;/strong>: Our team will review your inquiry within 1 business day&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Response&lt;/strong>: A member of our team will reach out to you by email or phone to address your questions or schedule a meeting&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Follow-up&lt;/strong>: We&amp;rsquo;ll provide any additional information or resources that may be helpful based on your inquiry&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="connect-with-us">Connect with us&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>While you wait, you can learn more about Peak Defence:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wingman AI Platform</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/solutions/wingman/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peakdefence.com/solutions/wingman/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="wingman-your-cybersecurity-ai-partner">Wingman: Your Cybersecurity AI Partner&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Wingman platform represents a fundamental shift in how organizations manage security. By combining artificial intelligence, advanced graph database technology, and intuitive design, Wingman transforms security from an overwhelming burden into a strategic advantage.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="core-capabilities">Core Capabilities&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="expert-guided-protection">Expert-Guided Protection&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Never navigate security alone. Wingman combines AI capabilities with expert guidance to ensure you&amp;rsquo;re always on the right path.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Key Features:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>AI-Enhanced Knowledge Base&lt;/strong>: Access security best practices and implementation guidance tailored to your specific situation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Contextual Recommendations&lt;/strong>: Receive suggestions that consider your unique environment, industry, and risk profile&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Expert Validation&lt;/strong>: Critical security decisions are validated by our security professionals&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Continuous Learning&lt;/strong>: The system continuously improves based on interactions across our customer base&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="intelligent-security-operations">Intelligent Security Operations&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Security at the speed of AI. Wingman&amp;rsquo;s purpose-built AI analyzes patterns across your entire security landscape, automatically prioritizing what matters.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>