<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Your Cybersecurity AI Wingman: Where Human Expertise Meets Intelligent Automation on PEAK DEFENCE - Your Cybersecurity Wingman</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/</link><description>Recent content in Your Cybersecurity AI Wingman: Where Human Expertise Meets Intelligent Automation on PEAK DEFENCE - Your Cybersecurity Wingman</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://peakdefence.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Backend / Full-Stack Developer</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/careers/jobs/backend-developer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://peakdefence.com/careers/jobs/backend-developer/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="mission-connection">Mission Connection&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As a Backend/Full-Stack Developer, you&amp;rsquo;ll be at the core of our mission to transform how organizations manage security through the perfect balance of People, Process, and Technology. You&amp;rsquo;ll build the systems that power our Wingman platform, with a focus on implementing AI capabilities and creating intuitive user interfaces.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="role-overview">Role Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ll design and build the systems that power our Wingman platform, with a focus on implementing AI capabilities and creating intuitive user interfaces. You&amp;rsquo;ll work closely with our security experts to translate complex security concepts into elegant technical solutions that help our customers achieve better security outcomes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Example</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/posts/what-ai-means-for-your-security-team/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 04:14:54 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://peakdefence.com/posts/what-ai-means-for-your-security-team/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="what-ai-means-for-your-security-team---breaking-the-manual-cycle">What AI Means for Your Security Team - Breaking the Manual Cycle&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="the-real-world-impact-of-ai-on-security-management---from-someone-whos-been-in-the-trenches">The Real-World Impact of AI on Security Management - From Someone Who&amp;rsquo;s Been in the Trenches&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been through more security audits than I can count. Both, conducting them and being on the receiving end. I&amp;rsquo;ve sat on the auditor&amp;rsquo;s side of the table, watching teams scramble to provide evidence for controls they claim to have. I&amp;rsquo;ve been on the auditee side too, working late nights to gather documentation, chasing system owners, and frantically updating tracking spreadsheets.I&amp;rsquo;ve been involved in a ton of security audits, both as the one doing the auditing and the one being audited. When I&amp;rsquo;m the auditor, I often see teams scramble to prove they actually have the security controls they say they do. And when I&amp;rsquo;m the one being audited, I&amp;rsquo;ve pulled plenty of all-nighters gathering documentation, chasing down system owners, and frantically trying to keep those tracking spreadsheets up to date.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Client Success Security Consultant</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/careers/jobs/security-consultant/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://peakdefence.com/careers/jobs/security-consultant/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="mission-connection">Mission Connection&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As a Client Success Security Consultant, you&amp;rsquo;ll be at the forefront of Peak Defence&amp;rsquo;s mission to transform security management through the perfect integration of People, Process, and Technology. You&amp;rsquo;ll work directly with clients to implement our methodology, ensuring they achieve meaningful security outcomes rather than just checking compliance boxes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="role-overview">Role Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Unlike traditional consultants who primarily give advice, you&amp;rsquo;ll be hands-on in implementing solutions, driving adoption of our methodology, and ensuring clients achieve measurable security improvements. You&amp;rsquo;ll work across the entire security lifecycle: from initial assessment through implementation, optimization, and ongoing management.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Schedule a Demo</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/demo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peakdefence.com/demo/</guid><description>&lt;div class="meetings-iframe-container" data-src="https://meetings-eu1.hubspot.com/roman-jasins?embed=true">&lt;/div>
&lt;script type="text/javascript" src="https://static.hsappstatic.net/MeetingsEmbed/ex/MeetingsEmbedCode.js">&lt;/script>

&lt;style>
 .meetings-iframe-container {
 min-width: 320px;
 height: 700px;
 transition: height .2s ease;
 margin-top: 2rem;
 }
 
 @media (max-width: 640px) {
 .meetings-iframe-container {
 height: 800px;
 }
 }
&lt;/style></description></item><item><title>Thank You for Your Application</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/thank-you/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peakdefence.com/thank-you/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="application-received">Application Received&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Thank you for your interest in joining the Peak Defence team! We&amp;rsquo;ve received your application and our hiring team will review it soon.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-happens-next">What happens next?&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Initial review&lt;/strong>: Our team will review your application within 1-2 business days&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Screening call&lt;/strong>: If your qualifications match our needs, we&amp;rsquo;ll reach out to schedule an initial conversation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Interview process&lt;/strong>: Qualified candidates will proceed through our interview process, which typically includes technical discussions and team meetings&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Decision&lt;/strong>: We strive to make hiring decisions within 2-3 weeks of receiving applications&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="stay-connected">Stay connected&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>While you wait, you can learn more about Peak Defence:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>