<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Your Cybersecurity AI Wingman: Where Human Expertise Meets Intelligent Automation on PEAK DEFENCE - Your Cybersecurity Wingman</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/</link><description>Recent content in Your Cybersecurity AI Wingman: Where Human Expertise Meets Intelligent Automation on PEAK DEFENCE - Your Cybersecurity Wingman</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://peakdefence.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Backend / Full-Stack Developer</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/careers/jobs/backend-developer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://peakdefence.com/careers/jobs/backend-developer/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="mission-connection">Mission Connection&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As a Backend/Full-Stack Developer, you&amp;rsquo;ll be at the core of our mission to transform how organizations manage security through the perfect balance of People, Process, and Technology. You&amp;rsquo;ll build the systems that power our Wingman platform, with a focus on implementing AI capabilities and creating intuitive user interfaces.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="role-overview">Role Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ll design and build the systems that power our Wingman platform, with a focus on implementing AI capabilities and creating intuitive user interfaces. You&amp;rsquo;ll work closely with our security experts to translate complex security concepts into elegant technical solutions that help our customers achieve better security outcomes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Client Success Security Consultant</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/careers/jobs/security-consultant/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://peakdefence.com/careers/jobs/security-consultant/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="mission-connection">Mission Connection&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As a Client Success Security Consultant, you&amp;rsquo;ll be at the forefront of Peak Defence&amp;rsquo;s mission to transform security management through the perfect integration of People, Process, and Technology. You&amp;rsquo;ll work directly with clients to implement our methodology, ensuring they achieve meaningful security outcomes rather than just checking compliance boxes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="role-overview">Role Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Unlike traditional consultants who primarily give advice, you&amp;rsquo;ll be hands-on in implementing solutions, driving adoption of our methodology, and ensuring clients achieve measurable security improvements. You&amp;rsquo;ll work across the entire security lifecycle: from initial assessment through implementation, optimization, and ongoing management.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Schedule a Demo</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/demo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peakdefence.com/demo/</guid><description>&lt;div class="meetings-iframe-container" data-src="https://meetings-eu1.hubspot.com/roman-jasins?embed=true">&lt;/div>
&lt;script type="text/javascript" src="https://static.hsappstatic.net/MeetingsEmbed/ex/MeetingsEmbedCode.js">&lt;/script>

&lt;style>
 .meetings-iframe-container {
 min-width: 320px;
 height: 700px;
 transition: height .2s ease;
 margin-top: 2rem;
 }
 
 @media (max-width: 640px) {
 .meetings-iframe-container {
 height: 800px;
 }
 }
&lt;/style></description></item></channel></rss>