<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Knowledge Management on Peak Defence - Your Cybersecurity Wingman</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/categories/knowledge-management/</link><description>Recent content in Knowledge Management on Peak Defence - Your Cybersecurity Wingman</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 07:15:40 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://peakdefence.com/categories/knowledge-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Risk Owner's Guide to Effective Risk Reviews</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/blog/the-risk-owners-guide-to-effective-risk-reviews/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://peakdefence.com/blog/the-risk-owners-guide-to-effective-risk-reviews/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="understanding-the-critical-role-of-a-risk-owner">Understanding the Critical Role of a Risk Owner&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In today&amp;rsquo;s intricate risk environment, a risk owner&amp;rsquo;s role is essential for maintaining an organization&amp;rsquo;s security and compliance. Risk owners act as the main custodians of designated risks, overseeing their continuous assessment, management, and mitigation. Among their most vital duties is performing comprehensive and efficient risk reviews.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This guide is designed to equip risk owners with a clear framework for conducting risk reviews, helping them effectively meet their responsibilities and enhance the organization&amp;rsquo;s overarching risk management strategy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Connecting the Dots: Why Security Knowledge Integration Matters</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/blog/connecting-the-dots/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 04:12:21 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://peakdefence.com/blog/connecting-the-dots/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://peakdefence.com/images/blog/connecting-the-dots.png" alt="image Impact of Security Knowledge Fragmentation">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="connecting-the-dots">Connecting the Dots&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There is a troubling pattern that we have seen in enterprises of all sizes: &lt;strong>fragmented security knowledge&lt;/strong>. And in today&amp;rsquo;s fast-evolving landscape, this fragmentation is more &amp;ldquo;dangerous&amp;rdquo; than ever. Just like the parable of the blind men and the elephant—where each man touches a different part and describes a completely different animal - teams often work with partial views of their security posture, leading to serious blind spots and ineffective decision-making.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>