<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cross-Functional on Peak Defence - Your Cybersecurity Wingman</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/tags/cross-functional/</link><description>Recent content in Cross-Functional on Peak Defence - Your Cybersecurity Wingman</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 07:15:40 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://peakdefence.com/tags/cross-functional/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>From Principles to Practice: How Time Horizons Transform Security Planning</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/blog/how-time-horizons-transform-security-planning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peakdefence.com/blog/how-time-horizons-transform-security-planning/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://peakdefence.com/images/blog/time-horizons-planning.png" alt="Time Horizons Transform Security Planning">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Planning can be super helpful or just annoying overhead – it all depends on whether you hit the right balance. This is true for pretty much everything, not just security. Finding this balance is key to getting the right velocity – not about being fast or slow in absolute terms, but moving forward steadily without rushing and creating more problems than you solve.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I going to share where we&amp;rsquo;ve found the sweet spot in planning for information security, and how this approach can help teams stop spinning their wheels and start making tangible progress.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Introduction to the Peak Defence Method</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/resources/method/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peakdefence.com/resources/method/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="why-this-methodology-exists">Why This Methodology Exists&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Security in today&amp;rsquo;s organizations faces a fundamental challenge: the approaches that worked in the past are failing to deliver sustainable value in increasingly complex, fast-moving environments.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This statement is likely to stay true for as long as environments we operate in keep changing, and that might always be the case, at least for most of the organizations. Despite growing security investments, many struggle with:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Security teams isolated from the business, creating friction rather than enablement&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Security controls that focus on prevention but fail to adapt when breaches occur&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Security work that expands indefinitely without clear boundaries or completion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Siloed approaches that prevent effective cross-functional collaboration&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rigid methodologies that don&amp;rsquo;t scale with organizational growth&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The Peak Defence Method addresses these challenges through a fundamentally different approach to security — one that prioritizes resilience over rigid prevention, balances centralized expertise with distributed responsibility, and delivers visible value through bounded, focused work.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Planning Horizons</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/resources/method/planning/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peakdefence.com/resources/method/planning/</guid><description>&lt;!-- # Planning Horizons -->
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Effective security requires working across multiple time horizons simultaneously. Without a structured approach to planning, organizations typically face these common challenges:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Strategic initiatives get interrupted by tactical and urgent needs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Long-term architectural decisions lack follow-through&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Short-term work doesn&amp;rsquo;t align with strategic direction&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Teams lose context when switching between immediate and long-term work&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Security priorities constantly shift, creating waste and confusion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cross-functional dependencies create bottlenecks and misalignment&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Security requirements are introduced too late in product or business processes&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The Four Horizons Framework provides a structured way to organize security initiatives across different timescales, ensuring that both strategic long-term objectives and tactical immediate needs receive appropriate attention. It also creates natural connection points with other organizational functions, enabling more effective cross-functional security work. This chapter explains how organizations of all sizes can implement this framework at their appropriate maturity level.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shaping Security Work</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/resources/method/shaping/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peakdefence.com/resources/method/shaping/</guid><description>&lt;!-- # Shaping Security Work -->
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Security initiatives fail for many reasons, but often there is a common pattern: &lt;strong>they&amp;rsquo;re either too vague or too specific before implementation begins&lt;/strong>. Traditional approaches oscillate between these extremes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Too abstract&lt;/strong>: &amp;ldquo;Implement zero trust architecture&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Improve our security posture&amp;rdquo; lack clear boundaries and direction&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Too concrete&lt;/strong>: Detailed specifications that over-constrain implementation teams and can&amp;rsquo;t adapt to discoveries made during implementation&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Shaping security work is the critical process that bridges this gap. It creates &lt;strong>just enough structure&lt;/strong> to enable teams to deliver meaningful security improvements within fixed time constraints, while leaving room for adaptation and expertise.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Security Roles and Responsibilities</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/resources/method/roles/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peakdefence.com/resources/method/roles/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Effective security outcomes depend not just on what we do, but on &lt;strong>who does it&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>how responsibilities are distributed&lt;/strong>. Many security initiatives fail despite solid technical foundations because:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Security responsibilities are unclear or undefined&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The wrong people make security decisions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Crucial stakeholders aren&amp;rsquo;t involved at the right time&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cross-functional dependencies aren&amp;rsquo;t managed effectively&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Security requirements aren&amp;rsquo;t translated for different audiences&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Security responsibilities don&amp;rsquo;t scale with organizational growth&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The Peak Defence Method defines a flexible framework for security roles and responsibilities that:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>