<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>GRC on Peak Defence - Your Cybersecurity Wingman</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/categories/grc/</link><description>Recent content in GRC on Peak Defence - Your Cybersecurity Wingman</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 08:39:54 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://peakdefence.com/categories/grc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Risk Owner's Guide to Effective Risk Reviews</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/blog/the-risk-owners-guide-to-effective-risk-reviews/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://peakdefence.com/blog/the-risk-owners-guide-to-effective-risk-reviews/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="understanding-the-critical-role-of-a-risk-owner">Understanding the Critical Role of a Risk Owner&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In today&amp;rsquo;s complex risk landscape, the role of a risk owner is pivotal to an organization&amp;rsquo;s security and compliance posture. Risk owners serve as the primary stewards of specific risks, responsible for their ongoing assessment, management, and mitigation. One of the most crucial responsibilities of a risk owner is conducting thorough and effective risk reviews.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This guide aims to provide risk owners with a clear framework for approaching risk reviews, ensuring they fulfill their responsibilities effectively and contribute to the organization&amp;rsquo;s overall risk management strategy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Connecting the Dots: Why Security Knowledge Integration Matters</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/blog/connecting-the-dots/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 04:12:21 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://peakdefence.com/blog/connecting-the-dots/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://peakdefence.com/images/blog/connecting-the-dots.png" alt="image Impact of Security Knowledge Fragmentation">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="connecting-the-dots">Connecting the Dots&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There is a troubling pattern that we have seen in enterprises of all sizes: &lt;strong>fragmented security knowledge&lt;/strong>. And in today&amp;rsquo;s fast-evolving landscape, this fragmentation is more &amp;ldquo;dangerous&amp;rdquo; than ever. Just like the parable of the blind men and the elephant—where each man touches a different part and describes a completely different animal - teams often work with partial views of their security posture, leading to serious blind spots and ineffective decision-making.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>