<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Planning on Peak Defence - Your Cybersecurity Wingman</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/tags/planning/</link><description>Recent content in Planning on Peak Defence - Your Cybersecurity Wingman</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 12:20:41 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://peakdefence.com/tags/planning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Planning Horizons</title><link>https://peakdefence.com/resources/method/planning/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peakdefence.com/resources/method/planning/</guid><description>&lt;!-- # Planning Horizons -->
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Effective security requires working across multiple time horizons simultaneously. Without a structured approach to planning, organizations typically face these common challenges:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Strategic initiatives get interrupted by tactical and urgent needs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Long-term architectural decisions lack follow-through&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Short-term work doesn&amp;rsquo;t align with strategic direction&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Teams lose context when switching between immediate and long-term work&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Security priorities constantly shift, creating waste and confusion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cross-functional dependencies create bottlenecks and misalignment&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Security requirements are introduced too late in product or business processes&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The Four Horizons Framework provides a structured way to organize security initiatives across different timescales, ensuring that both strategic long-term objectives and tactical immediate needs receive appropriate attention. It also creates natural connection points with other organizational functions, enabling more effective cross-functional security work. This chapter explains how organizations of all sizes can implement this framework at their appropriate maturity level.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>